A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Vice Presidential Confirmation, Series N FA1359
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Vice Presidential Confirmation, Series N
1934
1957-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
FA1359
3.87 Cubic Feet 5 legal document boxes 4 letter document boxes
Scope and Contents
On August 20, 1974, recently sworn-in President Gerald R. Ford formally nominated Nelson A. Rockefeller to be Vice President of the United States, in accordance with the Twenty-Fifth Amendment of the Constitution. Over the course of the next four months, the U.S. Senate and the House of Representatives held separate, extensive confirmation hearings on Mr. Rockefeller's nomination.
During the hearings, members of the Senate Committee requested substantial documentation related to Mr. Rockefeller's financial and professional activities from the previous decade. This series contains documentation of the efforts by the legal department in the Rockefeller Family Office in New York to respond to those requests, as well as the resulting materials that were provided to the Senate Committee and federal agencies such as the FBI.
On December 19, 1974, Nelson Rockefeller was sworn in as the forty-first U.S. Vice President, having successfully navigated the confirmation process. He served until January 20, 1977.
Arrangement
This small series was originally housed in large binders. The order of the binders has been maintained, with folders on Mr. Rockefeller's personal trusts followed by personal finances. Within the personal finance documentation, there is no Volume 5. The final set of records comprises chronological runs of Nelson Rockefeller's official itineraries and appointments during the last 5 years of his tenure as governor of New York and during the 12 months before his confirmation as U.S. Vice President.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Vice-Presidents -- United States; Financial statements
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 1: Items 1 to 4, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Federal income tax returns for the trust for the benefit of Margaretta Fitler Murphy Rockefeller.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 1: Items 5 to 7, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Security holdings and summary of provisions of trust created by John D. Rockefeller Jr. for the benefit of Nelson A. Rockefeller.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 1: Items 8 to 12, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Investments held in trusts; Trust information, summaries of provisions, and assets held in trust for the benefit of Margaretta Fitler Murphy Rockefeller; Amounts remitted and income collection in 1973 in Nelson A. Rockefeller's two trusts.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 2: Items 13 to 23, 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Various income and summary documents related to trusts for Nelson A. Rockefeller, Margaretta Fitler Murphy Rockefeller, his children, his grandchildren, and Mary Clark Rockefeller; Deed for property on Bedford Road in Westchester County, New York.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 2: Items 13 to 23 (Box 1, Folder 4a)
  Item 15
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - Nelson A. Rockefeller Estate - Open in 2029
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Trusts Volume 2: Item 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Records of trusts for Margaretta Fitler Murphy Rockefeller
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 1: Item 1, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1967 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 1: Item 1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1968 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 1: Item 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1969 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 1: Item 1, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1970 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 2: Item 1, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1971 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 2: Item 1, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1972 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 2: Item 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1973 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 2: Item 2, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 3: Item 2, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1965 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 3: Item 2, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Copy of Nelson Rockefeller's 1966 federal tax return
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 3: Item 3, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  General ledger chart of accounts from 1970 for Nelson Rockefeller and Margaretta Fitler Rockefeller
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Copy of the Rockefellers' 1967 federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1968 federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1969 federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1970 federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1971 quarterly federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1972 quarterly federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1973 quarterly federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 4: Item 4, 1974 January-June (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' quarterly federal tax returns for the first two quarters of 1974. Note that there is no Volume 5. The next folder picks up with Volume 6 items.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 6: Items 10 to 21, 1964-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Note that there is no Volume 5. This folder picks up with Volume 6 items. Items 16, 19, 20, and 21 are labeled in the inventory as Inspection items and were not found in the file, versus those labeled as Copy items, as described below:
  1966 City of New York Resident income tax return; 1974 Statement of Net Worth; 1964-1973 Summary of Federal Income Taxes paid; 1974 Draft Statement of Net Worth; 1967-1973 Summary of Federal Income Taxes paid; 1967-1973 Summary of Federal, State, and City Income Taxes paid; 1974 Trial Balance: Income and Expense accounts; 1973 Trial Balance.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 6: Item 22, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Copies of federal tax returns for Nelson Rockefeller's Trust #1 from 1964 to 1973
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 6: Item 22, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Copies of federal tax returns for Nelson Rockefeller's trust #2 for 1965 to 1973
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 6: Items 23 to 41, 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Items 24 through 29, 32, 35, and 41 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1974 List of real property at Venezuelan estate; 1974 Allocation of expenses; 1973 List of dividends received; 1974 Worksheet of furnishings, jewelry, coins, real estate; 1974 Worksheet of autos and accounts payable; 1973 List of taxable interest; 1974 Worksheet of foreign income; 1973 IRS letter of exempt status for Third Century Corporation; 1971-1974 Correspondence on NAR debt to Winthrop Rockefeller.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 7: Items 42 to 47, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Items 44 and 46 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1974 List of autos, boats, and planes; 1973 Worksheet of taxable and tax-exempt interest; 1969-1973 Worksheet of tax-exempt income; No date Inventory card of album of prints by L'Epreuve
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 7: Item 48 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Catalogue sheets for various artworks owned by Nelson Rockefeller
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 7: Items 49 to 53, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Items 49 and 52 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1974 Summary descriptions of certain investments and affiliations; 1974 Memo of information on Consolidated Edison shares; 1974 Revised statement of net worth
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 8: Items 54 to 62, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  1974 Recognized gain from Hills Realty; 1974 Worksheet; 1974 Various Art expenses; 1974 Chart of accounts; 1974 Deductibility of out-of-pocket expenses; 1974 Joint office expenses; 1974 Memo on Monte Sacro S.A.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 8: Items 63 to 70, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Item 68 is labeled in the inventory as Inspection rather than Copy, and therefore was not found in the file. The other items are described below:
  1974 Sale of stock of NAR Farms of Ecuador; 1974 Memo on foreign loans repayment; 1974 Supplement to sale of stock of NAR Farms of Ecuador; 1970-1974 Transaction runs; 1968-1971 Gift tax work papers; 1974 Art maintenance expenses for 1969-1974; 1974 Note on cash advances
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 8: Items 71 to 78, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Items 73 through 75 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1974 Summary of notes receivable; 1974 Summary of accounts receivable; 1973 Letter of IRS classification for Museum of Primitive Art; 1973-1974 Correspondence and Form 990 for Third-Century Corporation; 1974 Memo of sale of stock of Fazenda Bodoquena S.A.
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 9: Items 79 to 82, 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Items 79 and 80 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1974 Summary of Gifts compiled for 1957 to 1974; 1964-1973 Revised 10-year summary of federal taxes
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 9: Item 83, 1957-1966; 1974 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Copies of the Rockefellers' 1957-1966 and 1974 federal gift tax returns
- Requests for and Deliveries of Information: Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal Financial Volume 9: Items 84 to 87, 1957-1974 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  Items 84 and 85 were not found in the file. The remaining items are described below:
  1957-1974 List of loans to individuals; 1974 Answers to remaining open questions from Senate Committee
- Outdated Supplemental Financial Information on Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  Superceded information collected on Nelson and Margaretta Rockefeller's personal financial accounts and activities.
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 1, 1969 January-March (Box 5, Folder 39)
  Daily itineraries of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's official and social activities
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 1, 1969 April-September (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 1, 1969 October-December (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 2, 1970 January-February (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 2, 1970 March-April (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 2, 1970 May (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 2, 1970 June-July (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 3, 1970 August-September (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 3, 1970 October-December (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 4, 1971 January-March (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 4, 1971 April-August (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 4, 1971 September-December (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 5, 1972 January-April (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 5, 1972 May-September (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 5, 1972 October-December (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 6, 1973 January-March (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 6, 1973 April-June (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Gubernatorial Itineraries: Nelson A. Rockefeller Volume 6, 1973 July-December (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 January-March (Box 7, Folder 57)
  Daily appointment record of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's official and social activities; more detailed than the itineraries
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 April-June (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 July-September (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 October-December (Box 8, Folder 60)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1971 November-December (Box 8, Folder 61)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1972 January-March (Box 8, Folder 62)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1972 April-June (Box 8, Folder 63)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1972 July-September (Box 8, Folder 64)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1972 October-December (Box 8, Folder 65)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1973 January-April (Box 9, Folder 66)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1973 May-August (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1973 September-December (Box 9, Folder 68)
- Post-Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1974 January-March (Box 9, Folder 69)
  Daily appointment record of Nelson Rockefeller's daily activities; more detailed than the itineraries
- Post-Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1974 April-August (Box 9, Folder 70)
- Post-Gubernatorial Appointments: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1974 September-December (Box 9, Folder 71)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Telephone List, 1973 February (Box 9, Folder 72)